Finding Aid for the Ralph J. Bunche papers LSC.2051
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Photographs and Albums, 1924-1990; 15 boxes
  - President John F. Kennedy's visit to the United Nations, 1963 September 20 (Box 402, Folder 8)
    - President John F. Kennedy, greeted by Secretary General Thant and Under-Secretary for Special Political Affairs Bunche, upon his arrival at the United Nations, 1963 September 20
      Handwritten on verso of photograph: The President's arrival at UN 20, Sept. 1963, 11 a.m. Also identified in photograph are Don Thomas, Frank Begley, Pierre de Meulemeister, and Ramses Nassif.
  - Photographs, 1964 (Box 402, Folder 9)
    Includes photographs of Bunche with Martin Luther King and Coretta Scott King.
  - Yemen, 1964 February - March (Box 402, Folder 10)
    Bunche meeting tribal chiefs at Marab and Sana'a.
  - Gaza, 1964 April (Box 402, Folder 11)
    Bunche in meetings with UN officials.
  - McMaster University convocation, 1964 May 25 (Box 402, Folder 12)
    Bunche speaking and receiving an honorary degree.
  - University of Maine commencement, 1964 June 5 (Box 402, Folder 13)
  - Yeshiva University commencement, 1964 June 11 (Box 402, Folder 14)
  - Michigan State University commencement, 1964 June 14 (Box 402, Folder 15)
  - Yonkers Raceway, 1964 July 2 (Box 402, Folder 16)
    Bunche and his wife at the "United Nations Trot."
  - Photographs, 1965 (Box 402, Folder 17)
    Includes photographs of Bunche at UC Berkeley convocation, and with U Thant, Adlai Stevenson, and John V. Lindsay.
  - Photographs, 1966 (Box 402, Folder 18)
    Includes photographs of Bunche with Marc Chagall, with Vice President Hubert Humphrey at the UN, and at the Installation of the Chancellor ceremony at the University of Sussex.
  - Reed College, Portland, OR, 1966 February 13 (Box 402, Folder 19)
    Bunche at meeting with students.
  - Photographs, 1967 (Box 402, Folder 21)
    Includes photographs of Bunche at UNITAR meetings.
  - Uppsala, Sweden, 1967 December 10 (Box 402, Folder 22)
    Includes photographs of Bunche at wreath-laying ceremony at grave of Dag Hammarskjold.
  - Photographs, 1968 (Box 402, Folder 23)
    Includes photographs of Bunche, U Thant, Robert Kennedy, Jacqueline Kennedy and others at a private luncheon at the UN, Bunche with Vice President Hubert Humphrey, and with Josephine Baker.
  - President Lyndon B. Johnson's visit to United Nations, 1968 April 4 [and June?] (Box 402, Folder 24)
    Bunche, U Thant and others meeting with President Johnson.
  - 20th Anniversary of Palestine Operation Reception, 1968 June 19 (Box 402, Folder 25)
    Reunion party for veterans of the Palestine Operation at the UN.
  - Coretta Scott King and children, 1968 August 29 (Box 402, Folder 26)
    Bunche with Coretta Scott King and her children at the UN.
  - Photographs, 1969 (Box 402, Folder 27)
    Includes photographs of Bunche with A. Philip Randolph, with U Thant, and with members of the Shinnecock Nation.
  - Apollo 8 Astronauts UN visit, 1969 January 10 (Box 402, Folder 28)
    Frank Borman, James Lovell, William Anders and their families meet with U Thant and Bunche at the UN.
  - Colombia, 1969 March 12-15 (Box 403, Folder 1)
    Bunche meeting Alfonso Ocampo Londoño and others in Cali.
  - UCLA Bunche Hall Dedication ceremony, 1969 May 23 (Box 403, Folder 2)
    Bunche and his wife at ceremony with UCLA Chancellor Charles E. Young and Kareem Abdul-Jabbar.
    - Ruth Bunche, Ralph J. Bunche, and Lew Alcindor (Kareem Abdul-Jabbar) in front of Bunche Hall, UCLA, 1969
    - Ralph J. Bunche and Charles E. Young in front of Bunche Hall, UCLA, 1969
      Photo taken at the dedication of Bunche Hall, UCLA.
    - Ralph J. Bunche and Charles E. Young in front of Bunche Hall, UCLA, 1969
  - Bangkok, Thailand, 1969 July (Box 403, Folder 3)
    Bunche and his daughter Joan at meetings at Kasetsart University.
  - India, 1969 July (Box 403, Folder 4)
    Bunche with his wife and daughter Joan at the Taj Mahal and at Gandhi's tomb.
  - Cyprus, 1969 August (Box 403, Folder 5)
    Includes photographs of Bunche meeting Makarios III, Archbishop of Cyprus, and others.
  - Photographs, 1970 (Box 403, Folder 6)
    Includes photographs of Apollo 11 astronauts presenting a moon rock to the UN.
  - [India], undated (Box 403, Folder 7)
    Includes photographs of Bunche meeting with Jawaharlal Nehru and others.
  - Italy, undated (Box 403, Folder 8)
    Photographs and negatives of St. Peter's in Rome and other places in Italy.
  - United Nations (1 of 2), no date (Box 403, Folder 9)
    Bunche at the United Nations, and on travel assignments. Includes photographs of Trygve Lie, Jawarhalal Nehru, U Thant, Doreen Daughton Mashler, Marc Chagall, Carol Channing and Nnamdi Azikiwe.
  - United Nations (2 of 2), no date (Box 403, Folder 10)
    Bunche at the United Nations, and on travel assignments. Includes photographs taken in Israel, Rome, Salzburg and elsewhere.
  - Social events, no date (Box 403, Folder 11)
    Includes photographs of Bunche at parties, dinners, receptions, etc. mostly in New York, with a few from California and Washington, DC.
  - Unidentified places, no date (Box 403, Folder 12)
    Bunche at ceremonies, conferences and social events in unidentified places.
  - Portraits (1 of 2), no date (Box 404, Folder 1)
  - Portraits (2 of 2), no date (Box 404, Folder 2)
  - Autographed, no date (Box 404, Folder 3)
  - United Nations Office, no date (Box 404, Folder 4)
  - Unidentified places, no date (Box 404, Folder 5)
    Unidentified landscapes.
  - Negatives, unidentified, no date (Box 404, Folder 6)
  - Alienated photo envelopes and transmittal memoranda, no date (Box 404, Folder 7)
  - Album, New York City Reception for Bunche, Acting UN Mediator for Palestine, 1949 June 9 (Box 405, Folder 1)
    Includes photographs of Bunche meeting with Mayor William O'Dwyer and other dignitaries.
  - Album, Brooklyn Jewish Hospital, 1951 September (Box 405, Folder 2)
    Bunche's tour and meeting at Brooklyn Jewish Hospital.
  - Album, Southern Illinois University commencement, 1961 June (Box 405, Folder 3)
    Commencement ceremony, at which Bunche spoke and received an honorary degree.
  - Album, Rockefeller Foundation 50th Anniversary Meeting, 1963 April 3 (Box 405, Folder 4)
    Board of Trustees meeting.
  - Album, United Nations Truce Supervision Organization Visit, 1966 July 5-7 (Box 405, Folder 5)
    Israel, with dedication page signed by Lt. General Odd Bull.
  - Album, Bunche Hall Dedication Ceremony, UCLA, 1969 May 23 (Box 405, Folder 6)
    Bunche, Charles E. Young and other UCLA administrators at the dedication of Bunche Hall.
  - Album, Family of Man Awards Dinner, 1970 October 26 (Box 405, Folder 7)
    Album from the Council of Churches of the City of New York dinner presenting The Family of Man Award to Mayor John V. Lindsay.
  - Album, Peace Form One Dedication Ceremony (1 of 2), 1980 (Box 406, Folder 1)
    Photographs and ephemera from the ceremony dedicating the "Peace Form One" sculpture at the United Nations on September 15, 1980.
  - Album, Peace Form One Dedication Ceremony (2 of 2), 1980 (Box 406, Folder 2)
    Photographs and ephemera from the ceremony dedicating "Peace Form One" sculpture at the United Nations.
  - Album, Ralph Bunche commemorative stamp ceremony, 1982 (Box 406, Folder 3)
    Ceremony at United Nations for issue of Ralph Bunche commemorative stamp.
  - Album, no date (Box 406, Folder 4)
    Photographs of Bunche and family throughout his career.
  - Album, no date (Box 406, Folder 5)
  - Album, no date (Box 406, Folder 6)
    Photographs of Bunche throughout his career. Includes autographed photograph of General William O. Riley.
  - Bunche at home and with family, [1950-1970] (Box 407, Folder 1)
    Photographs of Bunche in his garden (taken by Alfred Eisenstaedt for Life magazine) and with his wife and children.
  - Photographs, 1944-1970 (Box 407, Folder 2)
    Photographs of Bunche with General William J. Donovan and Felix Frankfurter (1949), at Harvard University (1949), with Harpo Marx (1962), with President Lyndon Johnson (1963, 1968), and with President Richard Nixon (1970).
  - Academy Award Ceremony, 1951 (Box 407, Folder 3)
    Bunche at Academy Awards Ceremony, Pantages Theater, Los Angeles, CA. Includes photographs with Fred Astaire, Joseph Manciewicz, George Sanders and Darryl F. Zanuck. See also box 399, folder 12.
  - Yemen, 1963 (Box 407, Folder 4)
    Bunche arriving at the Republican Palace in Sana'a.
    - Ralph J. Bunche arriving in Yemen, 1963
  - Bunche in UN office, 1965 (Box 407, Folder 5)
    - Ralph J. Bunche, portrait, 1966
  - Bunche and Josephine Baker, undated (Box 407, Folder 6)
    Bunche and his wife meeting Josephine Baker.
  - Photographs, undated (Box 407, Folder 7)
    Includes photographs of Bunche at unidentified honorary degree ceremonies, and at the UN.
  - Album, Bunche children, [c. 1950] (Box 408, Folder 1)
    Joan, Jane and Ralph, Jr.
  - Album, 1929-47 (Box 408, Folder 2)
    Bunche, his wife and children, and other relatives and family friends.
  - Album, "Our Jane", 1966 (Box 408, Folder 3)
    Photograph album compiled by Ruth Bunche after Jane's death, includes pictures from throughout Jane's life, and of her children.
  - Album, Japan, 1960 (Box 409, Folder 1)
    Bunche, his wife and son during a visit to Japan.
  - Album, Golden Key Award Ceremony, 1962 (Box 410, Folder 1)
    Bunche with his former teacher, Emma Belle Sweet.
  - Album, Dedication Ceremonies of the Ralph J. Bunche School, 1972 June 13 (Box 411, Folder 1)
  - "The Peace Maker" by K. Ying Fung, [1949] (Box 432, Folder 5)
  - State Department, 1945 May 2 (Box 432, Folder 6)
- Honorary Degrees, Awards, and Trophies, 1932-1971; 21 boxes
  This series contains honorary degrees, awards, certificates of recognition, trophies and plaques awarded to Bunche. Also found in this series are materials related to his receipt of the Nobel Peace Prize (1950). City and state resolutions in honor of Bunche also appear in this series.
  Materials are arranged into the following four sub-series: Honorary Degrees; Awards, Citations and Honors; Nobel Prize Materials; and Medals, Plaques, and Trophies. Materials are arranged within each sub- series by chronology or appropriate housing size.
  - Honorary Degrees
    - Colby College, 1932 June 16 (Box 412, Folder 1)
    - Lincoln University, 1947 June 13 (Box 412, Folder 2)
    - New School for Social Research, 1949 May 31 (Box 412, Folder 3)
      Includes program from event.
    - Oberlin College, 1949 June 13 (Box 412, Folder 4)
      Includes program and photographs from the event.
    - University of the State of New York, 1949 October 21 (Box 412, Folder 5)
    - Atlanta University, 1950 April 23 (Box 412, Folder 6)
    - Gustavus Adolphus College, 1950 June 4 (Box 412, Folder 7)
    - Columbia University, 1950 June 8 (Box 412, Folder 8)
    - University of Rochester, 1950 June 12 (Box 412, Folder 9)
    - Bloomfield College and Seminary, 1951 January 12 (Box 412, Folder 10)
    - Agricultural and Technical College, 1951 May 28 (Box 412, Folder 11)
    - Morgan State College, 1951 June 4 (Box 412, Folder 12)
    - University of Denver, 1951 June 8 (Box 412, Folder 13)
    - University of Colorado, 1951 June 9 (Box 412, Folder 14)
    - University of Michigan, 1951 June 16 (Box 412, Folder 15)
    - Ohio State University, 1951 August 31 (Box 412, Folder 16)
    - Ohio Wesleyan University, 1951 August 31 (Box 412, Folder 17)
    - Saint Louis University, 1952 June 3 (Box 412, Folder 18)
    - University of Rhode Island, 1953 April 23 (Box 412, Folder 19)
    - Boston University, 1954 June 6 (Box 412, Folder 20)
    - Fairleigh Dickinson College, 1956 February 10 (Box 412, Folder 21)
    - New York University, 1956 June 6 (Box 412, Folder 22)
    - Simpson College, 1956 October 6 (Box 412, Folder 23)
    - Bradley University, 1960 June 5 (Box 413, Folder 1)
    - Clark University, 1960 June 11 (Box 413, Folder 2)
    - Southern Illinois University, 1961 June 14 (Box 413, Folder 3)
    - University of Manitoba, 1964 April 3 (Box 413, Folder 4)
    - McMaster University, 1964 May 25 (Box 413, Folder 5)
    - University of Maine, 1964 June 5 (Box 413, Folder 6)
    - Michigan State University, 1964 June 14 (Box 413, Folder 7)
    - University of Nebraska, 1968 June 1 (Box 413, Folder 8)
    - Programs for Honorary Degrees, 1949-1964 (Box 413, Folder 9)
    - University of Liberia, 1960 January 8 (Box 425, Folder 7)
    - Wayne State University, 1960 May 19 (Box 425, Folder 8)
    - Williams College, 1951 June 17 (Box 425, Folder 9)
    - York University, 1970 May 29 (Box 425, Folder 10)
    - Wayne University, 1951 June 14 (Box 426, Folder 1)
    - Springfield College, 1954 September 24 (Box 426, Folder 2)
    - Virginia State College, 1950 May 29 (Box 426, Folder 3)
    - University of Toledo, 1966 March 10 (Box 426, Folder 4)
    - University of Wisconsin, 1966 June 5 (Box 426, Folder 5)
    - West Virginia State College, 1950 May 26 (Box 426, Folder 6)
    - Temple University, 1949 October 4 (Box 426, Folder 7)
    - Syracuse University, 1949 June 6 (Box 426, Folder 8)
    - Oversize Honorary Degrees (13), 1949-1969 (Box 430, Folder 1)
      Includes items that have been digitized.
    - Oversize Honorary Degrees (11), 1947-1970 (Box 430, Folder 2)
    - Oversize Honorary Degrees (10), 1952-1961 (Box 430, Folder 3)
    - Oversize Honorary Degrees (8), 1949-1964 (Box 430, Folder 4)
    - Oversize Honorary Degrees (3), 1949-1960; From Fairleigh Dickenson College, Brandeis University, and Harvard University. (Box 432, Folder 1)
      Includes programs from events.
    - Degree and Award containers (Empty), [1932-1970]; Empty award tubes. (Box 470, Folder 1)
      For exhibit use only.
  - Awards, Citations, and Honors
    - Awards, certificates, and citations (3), undated (Box 413, Folder 9)
    - Awards, certificates, and citations (6), 1937-1949 (Box 413, Folder 10)
    - Awards, certificates, and citations (16), 1950-1970 (Box 413, Folder 11)
    - Institute for the Peaceful Relation of All Races of Men, undated; Leather folio. (Box 413, Folder 12)
    - Seattle World Affairs Council, citation, undated; Includes photograph. (Box 413, Folder 13)
    - Certificate of Honors at Graduation, UCLA, 1927; Framed facsimile and original. (Box 413, Folder 14)
    - American Association for the United Nations, Annual Award, 1949 May 9 (Box 413, Folder 15)
    - National Education Association of the United States, Certificate of Recognition, 1951 January (Box 413, Folder 16)
    - Award of the Silver Buffalo, Boy Scouts of America, 1951 May 26 (Box 413, Folder 17)
    - Prize of Human Rights, Academy of Human Rights, 1952 December 10 (Box 413, Folder 18)
    - Lord & Taylor Award, 1956 (Box 413, Folder 19)
      Includes program from event
    - Albert Gallatin Award, 1959 January 28 (Box 413, Folder 20)
    - Honorary Life Membership, Southern Illinois University Alumni Association, 1961 June 14 (Box 413, Folder 21)
    - General Federation of Women's Clubs, Recognition, 1964 June (Box 413, Folder 22)
    - Certificate of Appreciation, City of New York, 1965 April 27 (Box 414, Folder 1)
    - President's Cabinet Award, University of Detroit, 1969 April 16 (Box 414, Folder 2)
    - City, State, and Federal awards and resolutions in honor of Bunche, 1950-1970 (Box 430, Folder 5)
    - Awards, certificates, and citations (13), 1949-1969 (Box 430, Folder 6)
    - Awards in honor of Ruth H. Bunche (4), 1952-1956 (Box 430, Folder 7)
    - Alienated biographies and introductions to oversize awards and honorary degrees., undated (Box 430, Folder 8)
    - Awards and citations (3), 1952-1964 (Box 432, Folder 2)
    - City Resolutions honoring Bunche (2), 1954-1966 (Box 432, Folder 3)
    - Greetings presentations (3), 1954-1967 (Box 432, Folder 4)
    - Oversized awards and certificates of recognition, 1949-1971 (Box 433, Folder 4)
    - City and State Resolutions in honor of Bunche, 1949-1969 (Box 433, Folder 5)
  - Nobel Prize Materials
    - Research Material for Nobel Speech and Scandinavian Visit, 1948-1950 (Box 415, Folder 1)
    - Collected Itineraries for Scandinavian Visit, 1950-1951 (Box 415, Folder 2)
    - Acceptance Statements and other speeches, manuscript drafts, 1950 (Box 415, Folder 3)
    - Nobel Prize Statement of Acceptance, manuscript draft, 1950 (Box 415, Folder 4)
      - Statement to be made by Ralph J. Bunche, Principal Director, Department of Trusteeship and Information for Non-Self Governing Territories, United Nations, on the occasion of the presentation of the Nobel Peace Prize, 10 December 1950 at 1:00 p.m. (draft), 1950 December 10
    - Statement of Acceptance and Nobel Speeches, 1950 (Box 415, Folder 5)
      - Some reflections on peace in our time: Nobel Lecture, delivered at Oslo, December 11, 1950, 1950 December 11
        On front cover: Les Prix Nobel en 1950.
        Pamphlet published in 1951.
    - Statement of Acceptance and Nobel Speeches, offprints and reprints, 1950 (Box 415, Folder 6)
    - Official Statements on Bunche receiving Nobel Prize, 1950 (Box 415, Folder 7)
      - Ralph Bunche: address delivered by Governor Gunnar Jahn at the presentation of the Nobel Peace Prize, December 10, 1950, 1950 December 10
      - Statement by Dr. Ralph Bunche on receiving news of award of Nobel Prize for Peace, 1950 September 22
    - Les Prix Nobel en 1950, programs (Box 415, Folder 8)
    - Nobel Peace Prize Code of Statutes and Foundation Calendar, 1959-1964 (Box 415, Folder 9)
  - Medals, Plaques, and Trophies
    - Presidential Medal Freedom, 1963 (Box 416, Folder 1)
    - Key to the City of Toledo, glass key, undated (Box 417, Folder 1)
    - Yale Key to Tomorrow, gold key, 1962 (Box 417, Folder 2)
    - Award from Norwegian UNA Children, engraved metal plate, 1950 (Box 417, Folder 3)
    - Life Membership Tomas Jefferson High School Alumni Association, engraved metal plate, undated (Box 417, Folder 4)
    - Life Membership Dexter Fellows Tent, engraved metal plate, undated (Box 417, Folder 5)
    - Roosevelt University Diamond Jubilee Dinner, paperweight, 1959 (Box 417, Folder 6)
    - United Nations Emergency Force, paperweight, undated (Box 417, Folder 7)
    - Distinguished Service Award, plaque, undated (Box 418, Folder 1)
    - Certificate of Honorary Citizenship to Lubbock, Texas, plaque, 1967 (Box 418, Folder 2)
    - Lester B. Pearson International Award, plaque, 1970 (Box 418, Folder 3)
    - Jewish War Veterans Award for Advancement and Betterment of Mankind, plaque, 1950 (Box 419, Folder 1)
    - Latin American Institute International Service Award, plaque, 1950 (Box 419, Folder 2)
    - Men's Club of Congregation B'nai Deshuram Brotherhood Award, framed award, 1959 (Box 420, Folder 1)
    - New York City Police Department Guardian's Association Award, plaque, 1957 (Box 420, Folder 2)
    - UCLA Achievement Award, plaque, 1949 (Box 421, Folder 1)
    - Royal Canadian Air Force, plaque, 1963 (Box 421, Folder 2)
    - Johnny Baker Post 291, American Legion, plaque, 1949 (Box 421, Folder 3)
    - Queens City Bar Association Liberty Bell Award, plaque, 1967 (Box 421, Folder 4)
    - Lafayette High School Amity Award, plaque, 1961 (Box 421, Folder 5)
    - Veterans Association Chapter 369 Distinguished Service, plaque, 1965 (Box 421, Folder 6)
    - Horatio Alger Award of American Schools & Colleges Association, plaque, 1952 (Box 421, Folder 7)
    - National Sunday School and BTU Congress Award, plaque, 1955 (Box 421, Folder 8)
    - First Annual Student Council Human Relations Award, plaque, 1952 (Box 421, Folder 9)
    - Third Ethiopian Brigade in Congo, plaque, 1962 (Box 421, Folder 10)
    - Honorable Lubbock Chamber of Commerce, plaque, undated (Box 421, Folder 11)
    - Midwood High School FDR Award, plaque, 1951 (Box 421, Folder 12)
    - UN Association of New York, plaque, 1971 (Box 421, Folder 13)
    - National Council of Jewish Women, trophy base, 1963 (Box 421, Folder 14)
    - Legion of Guardsmen Award, plaque, 1950 (Box 422, Folder 1)
    - Diggs Enterprises Honorable Merit Award, plaque, 1956 (Box 422, Folder 2)
    - Hadassah Long Island First Citizen, plaque, 1953 (Box 422, Folder 3)
    - New York University, School of Education, Graduate Students Organization, plaque, 1955 (Box 422, Folder 4)
    - People's Independent Church of Christ Award, plaque, 1958 (Box 422, Folder 5)
    - New York State Bar Association Citizenship Award, plaque, 1967 (Box 422, Folder 6)
    - Chapman College, plaque, 1965 (Box 422, Folder 7)
    - Award by Enoch Grand Lodge, plaque, 1949 (Box 422, Folder 8)
    - Omega Psi Phi Fraternity Distinguished Service, plaque, undated (Box 422, Folder 9)
    - Symphony of New World Incorporated, plaque, 1972 (Box 422, Folder 10)
    - New York World's Fair Opening Day, medal and base, 1964 April 22 (Box 423, Folder 1)
    - Franklin Award, medal, 1964 (Box 423, Folder 2)
    - Detroit University President's Cabinet Award, medal, 1969 April 16 (Box 423, Folder 3)
    - Xavier University of Louisiana Drexel Award, medal, 1949 December 15 (Box 423, Folder 4)
    - Freedoms Foundation Award, medal, 1950 (Box 423, Folder 5)
    - Williamsburg Settlement Award, medal, 1954 May 16 (Box 423, Folder 6)
    - National Institute of Social Sciences Award, medal, undated (Box 423, Folder 7)
    - UCLA Distinguished Service Award, medal, 1967 (Box 423, Folder 8)
    - Third Order of St. Francis Award, medal, undated (Box 423, Folder 9)
    - Detroit's 250th Birthday Festival, medal, 1951 (Box 423, Folder 10)
    - Theodore Roosevelt Association Medal of Honor, undated (Box 423, Folder 11)
    - Moscow University, medal, undated (Box 423, Folder 12)
    - Zeta Beta Tau Richard Gottheil Award, medal, 1961 (Box 423, Folder 13)
    - Thomas Jefferson Highschool, medal, 1966 (Box 423, Folder 14)
    - Honorary Duchy of Duluth, medal, undated (Box 423, Folder 15)
    - Boy Scouts of America, medal, 1964 (Box 423, Folder 16)
    - UNEF Service of Peace Award, medal and lapel pins, undated (Box 423, Folder 17)
    - Unidad Integral Piloto de los Derechos Humanos, medal, undated (Box 423, Folder 18)
    - Father of the Year Award, medals (2), 1949 (Box 423, Folder 19)
    - Howard University Annual Student Council Award, medal, 1935 (Box 423, Folder 20)
    - Elijah P. Lovejoy Medal, medal, 1951 (Box 423, Folder 21)
    - Benjamin Franklin Highschool Community Service Award, medal, 1958 (Box 423, Folder 22)
    - New York City's 300 Anniversary presented by Mayor Robert Wagner, medal, 1964 (Box 423, Folder 23)
    - Michigan State University Award, medal, undated (Box 423, Folder 24)
    - Albert Gallatin Award, New York University, medal, undated (Box 423, Folder 25)
    - Research Institute of Amercia Award, medal and base, 1960 (Box 423, Folder 26)
    - Inter-Forensic Society Award, UCLA, medal and pin, 1927; Awards are framed. (Box 423, Folder 27)
    - Family of Man Award, medal, 1970 (Box 423, Folder 28)
    - People-to-People membership, pin, undated (Box 423, Folder 29)
    - National Honorary Educational Fraternity, pin, 1955 (Box 423, Folder 30)
    - Bud Billiken Chicago Defender award, plaque, undated (Box 424, Folder 1)
    - East Coast Model United Nations Conference, plaque, 1970 (Box 424, Folder 2)
    - American Brotherhood Award, plaque, 1949 (Box 425, Folder 1)
    - United Air Lines 100,000 Mile Club, plaque and card, 1951 (Box 425, Folder 2)
    - Thomas Jefferson Highschool Alumni Association, plaque, 1966 (Box 425, Folder 3)
    - Award presented by Los Angeles Mayor Sam Yorty, plaque, 1966 May 13 (Box 425, Folder 4)
    - Boyscouts National Jamboree, resin plaque, 1969 (Box 425, Folder 5)
    - Unidentified Awards (2), ribbon and metal plate, undated (Box 425, Folder 6)
    - International Teacher of the Year, trophy, 1969 (Box 427, Folder 1)